ELDEN LI

 $lielden@yahoo.com \diamond (408)\cdot799\cdot7027 \diamond http://linkedin.com/in/elden-li-1388a1141$

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

B.A. Computer Science

Spring 2021

GPA: 3.7

RELEVANT SKILLS

Courses: Data Structures, Machine Structures, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Security, Machine Learning, Databases, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, The Principles and Techniques of Data Science, Efficient Algorithms and Intractable Problems

Languages/Frameworks: Python(Django/Flask), Java, Javascript(Angular, React, TS), HTML5/CSS3, Swift, Numpy, Soup, Go, Arduino, Rust

Technologies: Encryption Technologies, Apache Spark, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Docker, Convolutional Neural Networks

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ServiceNow, Inc.

Software Engineer II

July 2022 - Present

 Contributed to the development of Key Management Framework, Column Level Encryption, Secrets Management and Code Signing teams

Software Engineer

May 2019 - July 2022

- Participated in an agile scrum team environment and gained customer facing experience through solving case tasks
- Created a secure storage framework that performs encryption/decryption on client side and stores only cipher-text in the database
- Supported full search features using an AVL Tree structure to preserve linear order on >1,000,000 entries of encrypted data

Software Engineering Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

■ Implemented Component State Validation, a page crawler that allows the user to validate the states (read-only, mandatory, etc.) of different UI components on for the ServiceNow's Automated Testing Framework

Blings.io

$Software\ Engineering\ Intern$

May 2020 - August 2020

- Implemented a user friendly web application in ReactJS/Typescript for company designers to easily interact with the product API when creating and editing videos
- Created an internal facing tool from scratch and learned to cater to developer productivity

PROJECTS

- Procare: Worked on a team to implement a data-driven workplace cloud infrastructure aiming to use ML to promote employee physical and mental wellness https://github.com/clairelin135/procare (HTML5/CSS3, Python/Flask, Google Cloud Platform)
- Peazy Pay: An iOS location-based credit card payment optimization app that uses a custom algorithm to inform the user which credit card will provide the greatest benefit based on the store they're visiting with the use of Google Maps API, Google Places SDK, other third-party APIs. https://github.com/armanvaziri/PeazyPay (Swift, Firebase)
- Privacy Guard (Cal Hacks 5.0): Designed a door-attachable magnetic sensor which, upon detecting movement, sends a signal to a Google Chrome extension that deletes all incognito tabs in 10 milliseconds https://github.com/f16falcona46/Calhacks_2018 (Tcl, Java, JS, Lua, NodeMcu, SQLite)

INTRODUCTION

I am a software engineer with over 2+ years of combined backend experience in encryption technologies, database management, and load balancing, but I'm open to join any fast paced software engineering team where I can learn from mentors in the day and feast with them at night. In my free time, I like to listen to music, play my guitar, and daydream about a life in a parallel universe where I play basketball for a living.